<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf8'?>
<response>

<comment>
<c_id>1</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[eldavojohn]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Green Product Development]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[Something interesting about tech companies is that concern for the environment is something that comes in usually later in the company's lifetime--after they've become millionaires. Because being green is, unfortunately, usually more expensive than the alternative.

Let's say you're making computer monitors in the early 90s and you start developing prototypes. You produce a 19" model that works well. Now, you could sink more money into the project and try to think of alterations to the design so that the chemicals inside the cathode ray tube can be safely removed before disposal ... but you're not even sure how many of these will be made and the market's not looking so good and you just want to start turning a profit. Plus you have all the other guys to compete with and they don't have any sort of thing like this nor does the government demand it.

Now it's ten years later and you're well off as a company selling tens of thousands of units each year. And you get a letter saying that because your product contains harmful chemicals, you've scored low in some newspaper rating for green companies. Plus, you want to tap the hippie market and score more profits. What do you have to do to make your product 'green'? Well, what would have been a design change in the beginning is no longer possible. Not only do you have to do that but you have to change all your manufacturing plants and work out the new source for the changes in these products. Plus you've got all that inventory and raw materials sitting around waiting to be made into new monitors. Well, it just doesn't seem worth it anymore. Even if you offer dismantling them as a service, you'll have to charge nearly as much as the monitor costs--is this even realistic?

The sad fact is that (most of the time) green products need to start out as green otherwise there's a very good chance their success will allow their manufacturers to overlook the benefits from being a green product. It needs to be a design time concern. Computers have valuable metals in them--can you see an easy way of extracting these? It's a pretty complicated process right now and I don't think it's very efficient. Nobody seems concerned with asking themselves where the product goes when it's done because initially they're not afraid of making an environmental impact. But if all companies have this shortsightedness then we're bound to suffer. As good little consumers, we buy the best product (hail capitalism) and we evaluate the products based on commonly held beliefs about quality and service. Unfortunately, we lack the foresight to imagine what we do with the product when it's (usually short) life span is over.

When your CD player breaks, what do you do with it? In the old days, if a phonograph broke, you took it to a skilled craftsman who fixed it. Today we throw things away and just buy a new one constantly. This is because the labor involved with fixing the old unit is more costly than a new unit. In doing this, we really build up staggering amounts of trash--the EPA estimates that U.S. citizens generate 4.6 lbs of trash per day [epa.gov]. Doesn't this seem like something that is going to become a logistical nightmare?]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>2</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>


<comment>
<c_id>3</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>4</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>5</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>6</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>7</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[aadvancedGIR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Too bad...]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I work on a Lenovo and it really behaves as if it was made out of recycled parts.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>8</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[Anonymous Coward]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Reducing waste]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[Of course Dell is up there, their Laptops displose of themselves!]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>9</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[goldcd]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[A reason why Dell and Nokia might be ner to the]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[top, despite what we might have thought (cheap evil makers of bits by the million) is that they sell huge volumes into offices worldwide. It tends to be companies that have to follow EU or national recycling guidelines on equipment - whereas the home user can just take his old monitor to the dump.
Makes sense if in the future you're going to have to dispose of a few thousand monitors, you'd ensure they offered disposal.
I am surpised Apple was quite so low on the list, but I guess as they're mainly selling directly to individual consumers, there's no real pressure on them to provide an ecologically sound(er) product - and if you were after a MAc, as they're the only seller.... (i.e. I could see a green company say choosing Dell over HP on that basis, but if you need a Mac, Apple have your sale).]]></content>
<replies>

<comment>
<c_id>10</c_id>
<parent>9</parent>
<author><![CDATA[Whiney Mac Fanboy]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Re: A reason why Dell and Nokia might be near to t]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I am surpised Apple was quite so low on the list

That's because you've been reading Apple's environment page [apple.com], which is peppered with feel good phrases such as "Apple helps to safeguard the environment" and "Apple recognizes its responsibility as a global citizen"

Apple talking the talk, but not walking the walk. Again.

Oh - and Dell & Nokia are near the top because they've made a greater effort to be green than the other companies.]]></content>

</comment>

</replies>

</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>11</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[no_such_user]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Rotten Apple]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[In 12/2005, my still-under-warranty iPod was gathering bad sectors on the drive. The "genius" at the Apple store said bad sectors were normal, and to just reformat it. After being quite persistent, he relented and gave me a replacement. But not before charging me a $30 "recycling fee". Bullshit! Given that they'll use all the parts, save for maybe the battery, again, I find it quite hard to believe that the battery costs $30 to recycle. FWIW, the way out of this fee is to purchase the Apple extended service plan. And then go back the next day and return just the service plan.

I know there's more to being green than just recycling batteries and parts, but Apple should be put under a microscope to make sure the money they're collecting for "recycling" is placed directly into "green" programs.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>12</c_id>

<author><![CDATA[gjh]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Not purely self-serving]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I have worked for Nokia since 1999.

Every desk in large offices - i.e. the ones that don't need to use local contract cleaning agencies - has had a 3-compartment trash bin under the desk the whole time, for recycling. The large Finnish offices are perfect examples of energy conservation in a cold country by the correct design to naturally distribute sunlight.

I play a game in Finnish offices where if I want to carry on working after 9pm, I have to jump up and run around the office every five minutes, otherwise the lights go out to save energy.

Conservation and environmental awareness to a culture in and of itself. You don't get a genuinely high ranking like we do unless you really mean it. It certainly can and does have short term economic benefits too, maybe that is even the strategy. Who knows what motive really went in to the policy, but I guarantee you that on the ground and amongst individual Nokia people, it is a culture and one that people are happy and proud of.

Things work on a different scale in small Nokia offices. I worked out of the now defunct Peterborough, UK office a couple of years ago. They used to recycle Friday's roast dinner into Monday's curry.

Obviously I am not an official voice of Nokia. Just a happy employee currently working on http://www.nokiaforbusiness.com/americas/firewall. html [nokiaforbusiness.com]]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>13</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[spurdy]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[More Green?]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[Shouldn't it be "greener" not "more green"?]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>14</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[DrXym]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Huh]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I'm waiting for PETA's report on how many ickle wittle bunny wunny's die to make PCs.

Seriously though, green policies can actually save you money. A PC which shuts down while inactive, or which uses cooler / low power chips is going to save you a quite a bit of money over its lifetime.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>15</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[c_forg]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Re: Count you syllables, please]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I always thought that was the funnest rule in grammar.]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>16</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[saleenS281]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Huh?]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[In this "post 9/11 world" it's good to label everyone you don't agree with a terrorist, because then everyone else will know *just how bad* they suck!]]></content>
</comment>

<comment>
<c_id>17</c_id>
<author><![CDATA[sane?]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[What would greenpeace rate?]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA[I've always considered there is something rotten with the political grandstanding of greenpeace.

A better question is what would be the truthfull assessment of greenness of greenpeace be? After all the produce nothing, the only effect they have is to prevent actions. They are the last word in paracitical, pointless organisations - dedicated to the idea that to do nothing is the best course. And yet the burn up valuable resources steaming around the world.

Take the money and energy wasted by greenpeace and put it into something with purpose that actually supports environmental progress rather than political positioning.]]></content>

<replies>

<comment>
<c_id>18</c_id>
<parent>17</parent>
<author><![CDATA[TapeCutter]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Re:What would greenpeace rate?]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA["only effect they have is to prevent actions. They are the last word in paracitical, pointless organisations"

Yes, they prevented the french from testing nukes in my "back yard", they prevented the franklin dam, and they stopped the senseless slaughter of whales (to name but a few of their achivements). Yes they are practical, but I wouldn't say they are the "last word". Pointless? I don't understand, I thought you wanted to "support environmental progress".

"Take the money and energy wasted by greenpeace and put it into something with purpose that actually supports environmental progress rather than political positioning."

It has a purpose but you don't agree with it or can't see it, millions of others support greenpeace because they are politically effective.

Disclaimer: I lived and worked on a sawmill, (old growth mountain ash), it was eventually shut down when it's 5yr lease ran out and the area is now preserved as a national park. From my personal experience neither side of the "green argument" has a monopoly on ignorant arseholes.]]></content>
<replies>

<comment>
<c_id>19</c_id>
<parent>18</parent>
<author><![CDATA[LWATCDR]]></author>
<subject><![CDATA[Re:What would greenpeace rate?]]></subject>
<content><![CDATA["Yes, they prevented the french from testing nukes in my "back yard", "
"Disclaimer: I lived and worked on a sawmill, (old growth mountain ash), it was eventually shut down when it's 5yr lease ran out and the area is now preserved as a national park"

Okay where do you live? The French tested nukes in the south pacific. The only place that I can think of that might have a saw mill near there is New Zealand. I am not so sure that they have have old growth ash in New Zealand. The only page I found on New Zealand forestry didn't list Ash at all. Even if you live in New Zealand you are claiming one really big back yard...

I don't like Greenpeace because I feel that like many other political groups on the right and the left they use fear as a route to power and that they feel the ends justify the means. Also I feel that they have done a great deal of harm to the environment by opposing nuclear power generation. The funny thing is one of the founders of Greenpeace thinks the very same thing.]]></content>
</comment>

</replies>
</comment>

</replies>
</comment>

</response>
